Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Your son has broken my trust!
Your son has dishonored
the agreement
both our families made!
Father, forgive me.
It's true that I pushed
Helena and Juanito
to be closer.
Because I still love Leandro.
Miss, thank goodness
you came out.
What are you doing here?
This opened my eyes to the truth
that Juanito could
never love me!
Because he's already
in love with you!
How did you know
where I am?
"The place
where it all began."
It was decided here
that we were to be married.
And I guess, we're also here
to end everything.
Good day, ladies.
Carmelita,
you don't have to avoid me.
I already accepted
that my love for you
is unrequited.
Sometimes, I wish...
I wouldn't have known...
That your heart
belongs to someone else.
Do you remember?
When I told you to meet me at the port?
Before I went back to Manila.
Aside from wanting to
give you the necklace I made...
There was something else
I wanted to tell you.
I apologize.
I think my eyes are starting to hurt.
Maybe because of the smoke
coming from the lamps.
Juanito...
you don't need to hide your tears from me.
You know back when I was young...
My Daddy...
I mean, my father.
He would always wipe my tears away.
And you know what else he does?
Let's stay like this a bit more.
Even if you didn't meet me at the port.
My only wish is that...
I should've been brave enough.
To ask you to
push through with our engagement because...
Because I am falling in love with you.
It's true that regret comes
in the end, Carmelita.
My only wish is to be with you.
I'm afraid of what could
happen to my family.
But whenever I'm with you...
My worries disappear.
My heart feels lighter.
And all my fears are gone.
Thank you, Carmelita.
I didn't expect you to
go against your father just to help us.
I know we're friends...
And you are close to our family.
But...
Are you doing this
because you have fallen
in love with my brother?
Yes, I love each and everyone of you.
And I also believe that
Don Mariano is innocent.
Truth must prevail.
Uh, Ignacio.
Captain Corpuz is in
Spain, isn't that right?
The ship he boarded to Spain
was intercepted under the
orders of General Seleno.
It's still unclear why he
was forced back home.
And...
I have news.
The lawyer that would
represent Don Mariano in court
was appointed by General Seleno himself.
I have a hunch.
I sense that...
They will deliberately lose his case.
That's why I will represent him myself.
I will defend your father in court.
Are you sure about this, my love?
Please forgive me, Carmelita.
I wasn't there when you and
Helena got into an argument.
She was probably taken away by her emotions
that's why she was able to do that.
She couldn't accept
that my brother has feelings for you.
I've known for awhile
that Juanito fancies you.
Especially after we saw you
and Leandro at that restaurant.
I didn't say anything because
he wanted to let you know himself.
I didn't expect that
you still love Leandro.
But... that's not true.
- Sonya?! Sonya?!
- Wait a minute...
- Wait...
- Ignacio! Juanito! Are you alright?
- Carmelita, what is it? Sonya?
- What happened, Sonya?
What is it?
Don't worry.
I'm fine.
My love, please.
Get some rest.
Being exhausted won't
do any good to the child
Ignacio, what do you mean?
My wife is pregnant.
I'm going to be a father.
Congratulations, Ignacio!
Sonya!
I am happy for the both of you.
Thank you, Carmelita and Juanito.
Sonya, what's the matter?
You don't look happy.
I am happy...
but I can't help but be worried.
Especially with everything that
is happening to our family now.
I'm not sure if we can protect the child
from all of this mess.
You know, I think...
All you have to do is love your child.
Because your love
will be the child's shield and weapon
against all challenges
they might face in life.
And they will always remember...
how much you loved them
and that they aren't alone.
No matter where they are.
Thank you, Carmelita.
I hope my child will be as
good and beautiful as you.
if ever she is a girl.
I just hope my niece
won't be as mischievous
and loud as she is.
I remember when we
were still chidlren, Ignacio.
You have always teased Sonya.
That is why we we're all shocked...
When you we're arranged
to be married by Father.
And now...
You're going to be parents.
Maybe you and Carmelita
will end up like that too.
Think about it.
You're already with her.
And...
She's ready to help even if
she's in love with someone else.
That only means you're special to her.
Maybe we'll only just be friends.
But I will admit...
No matter what I do,
I can't forget her.
Especially now that I know
she loves someone else.
When I learned about
her past with Leandro...
I hoped...
that she'll eventually be
mine once we get married.
But all hope was lost
when our wedding got cancelled.
Didn't you like someone else before?
Your heart belonged to Helena, right?
And yet...
How did you change your mind?
You want your wedding
to Carmelita to happen?
I don't know, Ignacio.
Things happened too quickly.
Since I met Carmelita,
she has always been on my mind.
Each encounter made
me fall in love with her.
Whenever she glares at me,
I just can't help but smile.
Even though she's grumpy.
Until one day, I woke up...
and she's the one my heart wants
If that's the case...
why did you meet with Helena
on the night of Thanksgiving?
I was on my way to
the festivities, Ignacio,
when Helena stopped me.
I told her I want Carmelita
and that I want the wedding to happen.
Suddenly, Don Alejandro
and Doña Soledad walked by.
I pulled Helena inside...
But without warning, she screamed.
Now I think she did it on purpose.
So it means, Helena really did betray us.
No matter what era,
there will always be traitors.
But can I blame her?
I also betrayed her.
I fell in love with Juanito
even though I know it'll hurt her.
Maybe that's how love truly is.
People will fight for
it no matter the cost.
This my plan
so that we can attend Father's hearing
without anyone recognizing us.
Are they serious?
Do we need to pretend?
What if we get caught?
They won't suspect a
thing if you speak in English.
Who taught you the
English language, Carmelita?
How can I tell them that after the Spanish,
the Americans will be next to colonize us?
And that English would
be our second language.
Madre Olivia taught me.
Very well. Come, let me prepare you.
Carmelita, you will be a
wealthy Englishwoman.
And the daughter of a renowned professor.
While Juanito,
is an impaired who
cannot speak English at all.
This is my wife...
And these are my friends from England.
Good morning.
I am Ashley Williams and
this is my husband George.
Alright! Alright!
There is no strong evidence that could link
Don Mariano to the rebels.
And lots of people come and
go inside Hacienda Alfonso.
They could have easily
hidden guns and rice in their stockroom.
I stand by my case that Don Mariano
is in alliance with the rebels.
I have witness who can testify
that he is planning treason
against the government.
It's true that Don Mariano,
as well as his son Sergio,
are allied with the rebels.
Check Don Mariano's back.
We have marked him with an X near the ribs.
Don Mariano, please stand up.
Stand up.
Turn around.
Turn around, please, Don Mariano.
How?
By the power vested upon me by the Court,
Don Mariano is hereby sentenced...
To death.
Juanito.
Mr. Valdez.
What is that?
A letter from Catapang.
I heard an innocent man
was sentenced to die,
and that they have used
my name to implicate him.
I am ready to help,
together with my comrades.
For the sake of the nation.
I will wait for your answer before dawn.
Leave your answer by the door.
- Catapang.
So it means Don Mariano
and Catapang are not allies.
But why didn't Don Mariano defend himself?
And who is behind all of this?
But Mr. Valdez...
why do you have the letter from Catapang?
Does this mean...
Mr. Valdez...
You told us that your brother
was murdered by the rebels.
We purposely spread that rumor
to avoid suspicion that
we joined with Catapang.
Because, we know...
That it was General
Seleno who killed my brother.
The two of them share whatever
money Diosdado collects.
But when Doña Julieta got sick...
He failed to give money for six months.
That's why General Seleno had him murdered.
We need your father.
We need someone influencial on our side
to open the minds of the people...
So that they will have the courage
to fight these corrupt officials!
We must save him.
Father! Father!
What are you doing here?
Don't!
You might get in trouble.
Mr. Valdez and the group
of Catapang helped us.
We'll escape together.
This is my fault, Juanito.
I trusted the person who convinced me
to put a mark on my back.
I didn't realize...
That he would betray me.
Who is that person, Father?
Let's tell Judge Fernandez.
It's not over yet.
It's not too late!
The sentence is already out.
It will be difficult to overturn.
Father, just come with me
Catapang's group promised to help us.
You will be a free man.
If I come with you and escape,
it's as good as a confession of my crime
against my post and the government!
But, Father.
Be strong.
Don't let anger consume your heart.
From now on, you are responsible
for your Mother and siblings.
No, Father...
Tell them I love them very much.
And don't be worried.
I am ready to face my fate.
No. Please don't say that, Father.
What is happening over there?!
Go now!
I won't accept it! I won't leave you here!
Leave!
Carmela-- Carmelita! Go ahead!
Just leave!
What is that!?
Go ahead!
Try to escape!
Stop it!
Stop!
Remember...
In this world, sometimes
there are battles we lose.
But when you fail,
it doesn’t mean you won’t rise again.
Carmelita...
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Carmelita...
Prepare yourself.
A lot of things and people
will be taken in place of Juanito.
Destiny is being rewritten.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
Don Mariano wasn't supposed to die.
Is everything changing?
Are all these changes because of me?
If yes...
Then I wish I can just
go back to my own time.
Because I don’t want to be the reason
someone’s life falls apart.
Dear child, these are
guava leaves I have boiled.
Clean Juanito's wounds using this.
Thank you very much, Mother Olivia.
I'd like to thank you as
well, Don Buencamino.
I was able to slip inside
this ship all because of you.
Before anyone else knew I was in Manila.
Remember, I'll come for you later.
I will be the one to take
you where Juanito is.
Do not ever come out of this place.
It's dangerous.
General Seleno might catch us.
My dear, wear this.
And as much as possible,
keep your head down.
You have to impersonate Mother Olivia.
This is the only way for
you to speak to a prisoner.
But...
What happens if they find out I'm lying?
You might be dragged into this as well.
To hell with being dragged into it.
Me following you here in Manila...
Is proof that I am prepared
to help you and Juanito.
Thank you.
Juanito...
Am I dreaming?
If not...
Then the Lord has already
answered my prayer.
To be able to see you again.
Don't!
You might get into trouble.
There will be consequences.
What is it?
Juanito...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn't--
I wasn't able to save
Don Mariano. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry...
- It's not your fault.
I'm sorry.
There, there.
Don't cry.
I'm sorry.
My father faced the
challenge of fate upon him.
It just saddens me to think...
I wasn't able to tell
him at the last moment
how much I love him.
And that I admire him.
Juanito...
Even if you weren't able to say it...
I'm sure he knew that you love him.
I know that he knew...
That you love him very much.
Don't cry anymore.
I'm sorry...
It's alright.
Carmelita...
Do you remember...
I told you once that...
It's impossible for someone's interest
to completely disappear.
I want to tell you...
Why I stopped painting and drawing.
Since I was a child...
It was my dream to
become a renowned painter.
But before I went to college...
My father told me he
wanted me to study medicine.
He did not stop me
from drawing or painting.
But...
I knew that if I continued
pursuing drawing and painting...
I wouldn't be able to
focus on my priorities.
That is why I decided
to follow Father's wishes.
I deeply admire...
And respect him.
I know.
Carmelita.
I know I have no right to
ask any favors from you.
But I just want to let you know
that whenever you're beside me...
I feel much braver.
And I am filled with hope.
Juanito...
I promise.
I will never leave your side.
Even if I complete my mission,
I know my heart will never
be away from you, Juanito.
I promise.
What is this for?
Just keep it with you.
Don Buencamino?
Is there a problem?
I heard this morning...
That Mr. Valdez has a warrant of arrest.
On grounds that he was the only outsider
sighted within Fuerte de Santiago.
On the night Juanito was
caught inside Don Mariano's cell.
What happened to Mr. Valdez?
The Civil Guards weren't
able to arrest him at his house.
But even now...
They still can't find him.
Let me wash your bruises.
Do not worry about me, Mother.
What do you mean, Sonya?
You and Ignacio were
arrested by the Civil Guards?
They arrested my father.
And accused him of being involved
with Don Mariano and the rebels!
He will be taken back to San
Alfonso together with Sergio.
To undergo investigation.
We have to be strong.
Let's just be thankful that
General Seleno agreed
to let us take Juanito home.
Instead of having him imprisoned in Manila.
What's the difference, Sonya?
We're stuck here inside our house.
It's as good as being imprisoned in Manila.
We are not allowed outside,
not even to attend mass.
Until when will we be prisoners here?
I want to see Father.
Are you hiding something from me, Juanito?
Where is your father?
Where is my husband?
Father was sentenced to death.
Father's gone.
- Carmelita, my dear.
- Mother...
How's Sugbu?
Come.
Alejandro, our youngest daughter is home.
My dear, I'm glad you came home safely.
Mother Olivia.
By the way, we have a visitor.
General Seleno.
Welcome back, Mother Olivia
Miss Carmelita.
We learned that it was Don Buencamino
who let Juanito into the ship to Manila.
And Juanito was with a woman that time.
General Seleno. What are you trying to say?
Carpio!
Bring the witness.
Bring him here!
Now...
Tell us all what you've seen.
I was working for Don Buencamino,
as a coal stoker by
the machine of the ship.
Last week...
Our ship was set to sail to Manila.
That's when I saw Sir Juanito Alfonso.
And a woman wearing a veil.
Who is this woman dressed in nun clothing?
I apologize, General but...
I wasn't able to see her face.
General!
Last night, Don Buencamino
and Mother Olivia visited Juanito.
I only went there to
treat Juanito's wounds.
I don't see anything wrong with that.
Moreover!
The law does not forbade
anyone from treating prisoners.
That only means, Mother Olivia...
That you came from Manila.
And you were on the
ship back to San Alfonso.
Mother Olivia...
I thought you were with
my daughter in Sugbu?
Are you suggesting
that I am the woman accompanying
Don Buencamino and Juanito...
On the way to Manila?
Here is my bilette.
You can clearly see the date
when I boarded the ship to Manila.
If that is so...
Then who is the woman with Juanito Alfonso?
Miss Carmelita.
How's your trip to Sugbu?
It's quite alright.
Alright, then.
What are the places you went to?
General.
From your tone...
Are you insinuating that Miss Carmelita
didn't come from Sugbu?
I didn't say anything like that.
I merely wanted to ask her.
Miss Carmelita.
Show the good General your bilette.
This is a big fumble for
someone in your position, General.
I understand that you
are only doing your job,
but you don't have the
right to accuse my daughter.
Punish the witness.
And strip Don Buencamino of his titles.
Where are you taking me!?
I apologize...
Don Alejandro.
Oh, by the way.
You are summoned by Judge Valenciano
at the town hall a fortnight from now.
Captain Corpuz made a statement.
He revealed that you were
the one who schemed...
The fake news
about Don Mariano
being involved with the rebels.
Your presence is expected.
I asked
General Sergio for help
but he raped and abused me.
I can see that
you're worried for Juanito.
But you should
probably accept
that maybe you're not
meant for one another.
The new leader of San Alfonso!
Governor Vicente Flores.
- Alejandro! Stop it!
- Father!
Stop it this instance!
You always go against
my word, Carmelita!
What were you doing
at the hospital?!
And why were you
talking to the girl
who testified
against the Alfonsos?!
Why did you stay quiet...
when Don Mariano
was sentenced?
Why?
What?
I am to be engaged
to Leandro?
Carmelita, dear, wait!
Juanito loved you
not because you were
pretending to be Carmelita...
But because you are Carmela.